FilmSub.lk — සිංහල උපසිරැසි සමඟ (Auto Sinhala Subtitles)
Baunei is a well-located village
in a place of hard stones,
above the plain,
under the mountain, and in the middle of the coast.
Everyone who goes by makes a stop for its beauty.
It looks so good!
All those who pass by crave it
for its beauty and its view.
- Good morning. -Good morning.
Now you show up? We already finished cooking!
- A little fiesta! - Good morning, ma'am.
Good morning.
What are you making?
Gathulis.
Is it sweet?
No, it's not sweet.
Potato and cheese.
If you had to judge your own health,
would you say it's bad, good, very good or excellent?
For the age I have, I'd say it's good.
- Good? Not excellent? -Excellent. Maybe excellent.
It can't be absolutely excellent.
For me, as I said before, faith and hope are the two.
So it's that. It's not down to my merit.
If I walk slowly, ten minutes.
When I was a kid, there were only wheat fields here.
Do you remember the post office used to be here?
- Yes. -Mrs. Lavinia worked there.
Yes, I remember that.
- Good evening! -Hello!
Where are you going? Out for a walk?
Did it heat up?
It won't be easy to warm it up quickly.
You have to stir it, then leave it alone for a little while.
You're really not good at this!
Where is the salt?
And the onion?
Check this out!
I had two aunts. One died at 103, another 102.
He's an old man!
I'm not yet as old as he says.
First, we milked the animals
early when it started to get light.
The wall wasn't there yet,
so we had to follow the animals everywhere.
I never liked going to school for writing.
Now she won't give you back your pen.
She's on the last one.
When I was 80,
a woman asked me about my retirement pension.
Everyone in my family was dying in their 80s,
so I said, "What's the point of asking for a pension?"
And now I've missed those 21 years of pension payments.
But you've gained in age.
- Has she always been single? - Yes.
Have you always been single, Aunt Gio?
-Yes. -True, she has always been single.
We take turns taking care of her every day.
We take her for a walk. We cook for her.
Even when she was younger, she was invited to lunch by all her nieces.
We never left her alone on Sundays,
despite us being busy with our kids.
We always considered her like a mother to us.
She doesn't have children of her own, but she took care of us.
Once, she was very ill.
We hospitalized her,
and at the hospital, she was always turned towards the wall
and wouldn't speak to anyone.
She wouldn't say anything, and we knew we were losing her.
So we started taking turns in groups,
and we fed her.
We held her head up
because she couldn't stand up.
You want to know something? When we come here, we relax.
We get to relax because she transmits serenity.
Please protect us. I ask for protection.
Please watch over us.
That's what I pray for.
Keep us healthy.
For my grandchildren.
To be safe.